Grove Press Records
Grove Press Records
- Publicity
  - Articles, clippings from newspapers, magazines, trade journals, etc.
    - How Barney Rossett publishes dirty books for fun and profit,Saturday Evening Post, 25 Jan 1969 (Oversize 13)
    - Operation Julie, 1978 (Box 1083)
      See also Scrapbooks: The Acid File.
    - Poets, 1960-1966; pieces by and about Ginsberg, Yevtushenko, Hollo, Corso (Box 1083)
    - Times Literary Supplement on Paperbacks, 1960 (Box 1083)
    - Miscellaneous Grove-related, 1954-1970; undated; most are reviews of Grove books or passing mention of Grove; includes article by Granville Hicks (March 1959) (Box 1083)
    - Miscellaneous unrelated to Grove, 1962-1970; undated (Box 1083)
  - Black Cat Kits, 2 folders (Box 1084)
  - Book cover repros, miscellaneous titles (Box 1084)
  - Book exhibits
    - American Anthropoligical Association convention, 1958 (Box 1084)
    - Combined Book Exhibit, 1958-1959 (Box 1084)
    - Combined Book Exhibit Conference Book Service, 1961-1962; 2 folders (Box 1084)
    - List of exhibits, 1698-1969 (Box 1084)
    - Major conventions, 1961 (Box 1084)
    - Miscellaneous showings, 1961; 1973 (Box 1084)
    - Miscellaneous, 1959-1962; notes, brochures, correspondence, etc. (Box 1084)
  - Book lists, cloth, 1959-1960 (Box 1084)
  - Book lists, Evergreen Books, 1958-1962 (Box 1084)
  - Book lists, Grove, complete list printed on small 9x3" sheets (Box 1084)
  - Book lists, unidentified, handwritten, typed, printed (Box 1084)
  - Catalog requests (Box 1084)
  - Catalogs
    - General, 1953-1963; 1968-1972,; 1985-1986; seasonal catalogs (e.g. Fall 1964); includes one folder of index cards listing publishers who were sent catalogs, etc.; 23 folders (Box 1085)
    - General, original layout for Fall 1958 catalog (Oversize 25)
    - General, 1973-1986; seasonal catalogs (e.g. Fall 1964); 13 folders (Box 1086)
    - Asian Collection (Box 1086)
    - "Catalog of books published by Grove Press 1952-1966", 1967; includes photocopy with annotations (Box 1086)
    - "Catalog of books published by Grove Press 1952-1967", 1968 (Box 1086)
    - "Catalog of books published by Grove Press 1952-1969", 1970 (Box 1086)
    - College
      - Drama and film, 1963; includes brochure, "A new teaching medium: The film-scenario book" (Box 1086)
      - Grove Press Books and Films, circa 1973 (Box 1086)
      - Literature (Evergreen Books), 1964 (Box 1086)
      - General, 1966-1968; 3 folders (Box 1086)
      - General, 5 folders (Box 1087)
    - Complete Listing of Evergreen Books Fall 1960 (Box 1087)
    - Drama, 1968 (Box 1087)
    - Evergreen Books, 1955-1962; 3 folders (Box 1087)
    - Library catalogs, 1967-1968 (Box 1087)
    - New Books for Young People, 1968 (Box 1087)
    - Psychology, Psychiatry, Sociology, 1960; 1966 (Box 1087)
    - Suki Books for Children, circa 1968 (Box 1087)
    - Vintage/Ballantine Grove Press paperbacks, 1977-1978; 2 folders (Box 1087)
    - Unidentified Grove, labeled "source copy"; appears to be photocopies of press releases (Box 1087)
    - Unidentified Grove, proofs, printed catalogs with corrections, one glass plate negative (Box 1087)
    - Other (non-Grove), 1957; Disque Vega Portefeuille Catalog (Box 1087)
    - Other (non-Grove), Laurel Editions, Stokes & Stockell Bokshop, Paperback Book News, Kroch's & Brentano's, others (Box 1088)
  - Censorship and obscenity
    - General, 1959; 1962-1970,; undated; clippings, magazine articles, reprints of legal decisions, etc.; 9 folders (Box 1088)
    - Eros magazine, Ralph Ginzburg, 1965-1966; includes copy of "Eros on Trial"; 2 folders (Box 1089)
    - Evergreen Review, 1965-1969; German banning of Phoebe Zeitgeist, library bannings, etc. (Box 1089)
    - Evergreen Review seizure, 1964 (Box 1089)
    - Justice William O. Douglas impeachment, 1970; criticism of Douglas during impeachment hearings included his defense of the film I Am Curious Yellow; 4 folders (Box 1089)
    - Lady Chatterley's Lover (Box 1089)
    - Letters, 1957; 1964-1967 (Box 1089)
    - Olympia Reader promotional piece, handmade envelope and four-fold brochure with text, illustrations, etc. (Box 1089)
    - President's Committee on Obscenity and Pornography, 1970 (Box 1089)
    - Rialto Theatre, 1970; clippings, correspondence (Box 1089)
  - College Department memos, 1958-1960; new book announcements (Box 1089)
  - Columbia Record Club, 1961 (Box 1089)
  - Complimentary copy orders, 1962-1965; 2 folders (Box 1090)
  - Council on Student Travel, 1959-1961 (Box 1090)
  - Dell Publishing memos and expenses, 1960-1961 (Box 1090)
  - Dell Who's Who of Laurel Editions authors and editors, alpha list with brief bios (Box 1090)
  - Evergreen Book Week, Montreal, 1960 (Box 1090)
  - Evergreen Book Week, San Francisco, 1958-1959; includes photographs; 3 folders (Box 1090)
  - Evergreen Book Week, Washington, 1959 (Box 1090)
  - Evergreen Books: A Checklist for College Classes (Box 1090)
  - Evergreen Books press releases for new books, 1961 (Box 1090)
  - Evergreen display racks, display rack mockups, order forms, photographs, etc.; 3 folders (Box 1090)
  - Evergreen Theater, East Hampton, 1960; 1968; fliers, clippings (Box 1090)
  - Examination copies, 1961; 1977-1978,; undated; mailings, lists, etc.; 3 folders (Box 1090)
  - General correspondence, 1951; 1956-1970,; 1973-1974,; 1979,; undated; 5 folders (Box 1091)
  - German Information Center photogaphs, contact sheets of candid photos of various people and places; handwritten on envelope is "Ute Erb Chains Around Your Neck" (Box 1091)
  - Globe Mail, 1962-1963 (Box 1091)
  - Harsh-Finegold (advertising agency), 1976 (Box 1091)
  - History Book Club, 1960 (Box 1091)
  - Layouts, miscellaneous (Box 1091)
  - LIFE article, 1969; correspondence with LIFE as well as copies of letters from readers regarding LIFE's article on Barney Rosset (Box 1091)
  - Mailing reports, 1959-1960 (Box 1091)
  - Mailings
    - Adults Only, for Evergreen Review and Evergreen Book Club (Box 1091)
    - Big 6 from Grove Press, Dear Dr. Hip Pocrates, Sammy Younge, Jr., Erotic Art, Evergreen Review Reader, Joy, and Rationale of the Dirty Joke (Box 1091)
    - Black Experience, 1969 (Box 1091)
    - Bookstore mailing, 3 for 1 (Box 1091)
    - Christmas in August (Box 1091)
    - Cleared by the Courts: I Am Curious Yellow (Box 1091)
    - College mailing, 1964 (Box 1091)
    - Drama mailings (Box 1091)
    - Freight's On Grove, 1984 (Box 1091)
    - Giant Dwarfs by Gisela Eisner, 1965 (Box 1091)
    - Racial Studies, 1967; Frantz Fanon, Malcolm X, LeRoi Jones, Janheinz Jahn, Amos Tutuola, Clavin Hernton (Box 1091)
    - Survival Kit for Our Generation, GI Rights and Army Justice, IV-F Guide to Draft Exemption, and Busted: What To Do Until the Lawyer Comes (Box 1091)
    - Three New Bestsellers from Grove (Box 1091)
    - Wisdom of the East series (Box 1091)
    - Miscellaneous pieces, 1961-1962 (Box 1091)
  - Modern Language Association, 1961 (Box 1092)
  - New York Free Press, 1967-1968 (Box 1092)
  - On the Evergreen Beat, 1960; clippings (Box 1092)
  - Order forms
    - Backlist, 1986; undated (Box 1092)
    - Black Cat, 1961-1964; 1968; 3 folders (Box 1092)
    - Black Cat and Zebra, 1969-1970 (Box 1092)
    - Cloth, 1959-1971; undated; 4 folders (Box 1092)
    - Drama and film, 1962; undated (Box 1092)
    - Evergreen Books, 1956-1962; 3 folders (Box 1092)
    - Evergreen Book News, 1959-1962 (Box 1092)
    - Evergreen Gallery Books (Box 1092)
    - Evergreen Paperbacks, 1962-1970; 2 folders (Box 1092)
    - Evergreen Profile Books, 1960 (Box 1092)
    - Grove Book News, 1960; undated (Box 1092)
    - Grove Press New Releases, 1962 (Box 1092)
    - Modern Library / Vintage Books / Grove Press / Adult paperbacks, 1972 (Box 1092)
    - New from Grove Press, 1968; 1971 (Box 1092)
    - Paperbacks, 1964-1971; 2 folders (Box 1092)
    - Psychology, Psychiatry, Sociology, 1958; 1960,; 1963-1965; 5 folders (Box 1093)
    - Whirlwind, 1975 (Box 1093)
    - Wisdom of the East series (Box 1093)
    - Zebra and Venus, 1971-1972 (Box 1093)
  - Paperbook Gallery Inc., 1959-1960 (Box 1093)
  - Photographs of authors
    - Negatives, A-Z (Box 1094)
    - Negatives, unidentified (Box 1094)
  - Photographs of books
    - Negatives, composite shots, includes a few color transparencies (Box 1094)
    - Negatives by title, A-E, 4 folders (Box 1094)
    - Negatives by title, F-M, 5 folders (Box 1095)
    - Negatives by title, N-T, 6 folders (Box 1096)
    - Negatives by title, U-Z (Box 1097)
    - Prints, composite shots, includes some board-mounted ad layouts (Box 1097)
    - Prints, A-Z by title, 3 folders (Box 1097)
  - Press releases, miscellaneous (Box 1093)
  - Production, miscellaneous, invoices, orders, proof sheets, etc. relating to printing and production of catalogs, ads, mailers, other forms of publicity (Box 1093)
  - Publishers Weekly Advance Book, 1957-1961; 4 folders (Box 1093)
  - Publishers Weekly tips, 1959-1962 (Box 1093)
  - Samples of publicity material, 1958-1959; undated; press releases, brochures, ads, etc.; 3 folders (Box 1093)
  - Scholastic Book Club, 1960; correspondence, printed material, etc. (Box 1093)
  - Scrapbooks
    For the three "Grove Press" and three "History" scrapbooks, material includes press releases, catalogs, order forms, photographs of books and marketing displays, reviews, clippings, advertisements, book jackets, etc. Original plain black binders were decaying and were discarded; titles given are those on the original binder labels. Items remain in original sleeves, but original black separator sheets in each sleeve have been replaced with white to protect materials.
    - "The Acid File", large binder with copies of articles, clippings, etc. about LSD (Oversize 30)
    - "Books for Fall 1953" (Oversize 38)
    - Advertising, 1952-1958 (Oversize 24)
    - Grove Press 1951 to 1953 (Oversize 15)
    - Grove Press 1954 to 1956 (Oversize 16)
    - Grove Press 1957 (Oversize 17)
    - [untitled 1], 1958-1959 (Oversize 18)
    - [untitled 2], 1958-1959 (Oversize 19)
    - [untitled 3], 1958-1959 (Oversize 20)
    - History 1959 (Oversize 21)
    - History 1959, cont. (Oversize 22)
    - History 1960 (Oversize 23)
  - Standing orders, 1960 (Box 1093)
  - Subterranean project, 1960; publicity campaign with MGM regarding Kerouac (Box 1098)
  - Suki Books artwork proofs, proofs of logo (Box 1098)
  - Sussman and Sugar Advertising, 1954; 1964-1970,; 1976-1977,; undated; last folder includes article about S&S resigning Grove's account due to Exner book; 5 folders (Box 1098)
  - Trade List Annual, 1958-1959; 1962-1964,; 1966-1969,; 1972-1973; 6 folders (Box 1098)
  - Trade List Annual, 1973; 1976-1977,; undated; working files, printed material (Box 1099)
  - Traveler's Companion series, book jackets, photos, negatives, lists, etc. (Box 1099)
  - Wisdom of the East series, 1958-1961 (Box 1099)
  - Zebra Books, clippings, correspondence, ads, mailings, etc. (Box 1099)
  - Zeta magazine, 1967-1968; includes large full-color promotional posters (Box 1099)
  - Zodiac Books, includes original layout for an ad (Box 1099)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 1099)